<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michael Johnson</title>
    <link>http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michael Johnson</description>
    <image>
      <title>Michael Johnson</title>
      <url>http://saturn.lan:8833/images/profile.jpg</url>
      <link>http://saturn.lan:8833/images/profile.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.154.5</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I Built Daemonless</title>
      <link>http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/why-i-built-daemonless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/why-i-built-daemonless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a FreeBSD user since the late 90s. From 2002 to 2010, I was a ports committer working on the GNOME and Multimedia teams. &lt;strong&gt;I have always felt more &amp;ldquo;at home&amp;rdquo; with FreeBSD.&lt;/strong&gt; There is a logic and cohesiveness to the Base System + Ports approach that just clicks for me in a way Linux distros often don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the world changed. The OCI (Docker) container workflow took over, and for good reason: immutable infrastructure and easy updates are incredible for sanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back on the Net</title>
      <link>http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/back-on-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/back-on-the-net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have owned &lt;strong&gt;ahze.net&lt;/strong&gt; for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of that time, this domain has been a quiet corner of the internet—mostly used for internal lab services, mail, or just sitting idle. I&amp;rsquo;ve rarely had anything public-facing or inviting for the outside world to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m changing that today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start documenting my projects, my experiments with FreeBSD, and the growth of the &lt;strong&gt;Daemonless&lt;/strong&gt; ecosystem here. This site is currently running inside a Daemonless Hugo container on my own infrastructure, which feels like the right way to kick things off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab Architecture</title>
      <link>http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/homelab-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/homelab-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My homelab has evolved significantly over the years. Currently, it&amp;rsquo;s a mix of heavy iron and efficient ARM devices, all orchestrated with Ansible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fleet&#34;&gt;The Fleet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mars (TrueNAS):&lt;/strong&gt; The primary storage engine. Bulk ZFS datasets, backups, and media library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturn (FreeBSD 15):&lt;/strong&gt; The CI/CD Core. Runs Gitea, Woodpecker, and DNS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupiter (FreeBSD 15):&lt;/strong&gt; The heavy lifter. Runs local storage and media services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPNsense:&lt;/strong&gt; The perimeter. Handling the network, firewall rules, and VLANs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pluto (FreeBSD 14):&lt;/strong&gt; My dedicated test box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunshine (Synology DS418):&lt;/strong&gt; Secondary backup server to Mars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venus (Linux/Fedora):&lt;/strong&gt; For the few things that absolutely refuse to run on FreeBSD (yet).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PiAware:&lt;/strong&gt; ADS-B flight tracker (built following &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flightaware.com/adsb/piaware/build/&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pibox (Linux/ARM64):&lt;/strong&gt; My low-power, always-on utility box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is managed via &lt;strong&gt;Ansible&lt;/strong&gt; stored in a private Gitea repo. Secrets are vaulted. Deployment is a single playbook run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreeBSD vs Linux: My Take</title>
      <link>http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/freebsd-vs-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://saturn.lan:8833/posts/freebsd-vs-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use both. I like both. But they feel very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt; feels like a bazaar. You grab a kernel here, a package manager there, a init system from over there (usually systemd these days), and stitch it together. It&amp;rsquo;s powerful, chaotic, and moves fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/strong&gt; feels like a cathedral (to borrow the classic metaphor). The OS is a complete, cohesive unit. The kernel and userland are developed together. &lt;code&gt;ifconfig&lt;/code&gt; works the same way it did 20 years ago. ZFS is a first-class citizen, not an external module.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
